## Ashwani Kumar V

Senior DevOps Engineer

- **\** +91 7989 121 975
- ✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com
- ♥ Hyderabad, IN
- in linkedin.com/in/avk-sd
- github.com/SimplifiedDev Ops

#### **SUMMARY**

9+ years of experience in IT field which includes 6+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through K8S & AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

### **KEY SKILLS**

Linux System Administration
Bash, Python Scripting
AWS Cloud
AWS Security, DevSecOps
Terraform
Ansible, Packer
Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Code
Commit

Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube Nginx, Apache Tomcat Jenkins, CodeBuild Docker, CodeDeploy Kubernetes, AWS EKS Helm Charts, CodePipeline

# AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform & Ansible Automation, Kubernetes Admin with DevOps Lifecycle

#### **Professional Experience**

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru Date: July 2021 – Till date

Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & DevOps Engineer

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad, Date: February 2015 – December 2017

Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

#### **Employment History**

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- 1. **Collaborate with software product development,** architecture, and IT teams to ensure releases are **delivered with repeatable and auditable** processes.
- 2. Responsible for **application Build & Release process** which includes Code Compilation, **Packaging, Security Scanning and code quality scanning**, Deployment Methodology and Application Configurations.
- 3. Architect and design the setup and configuration of CI/CD pipelines and support/resolve technical complexities to integrate various DevOps practices as part of CI/CD implementation.
- 4. Work closely **with product teams** to find the right **trade-off between business-specific** needs and state-of-the-art **CI/CD best practices**.
- 5. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **monitoring**, and **operations**.
- 6. Execute and automate operational processes quickly, accurately, and securely. **Provide solutions to increase visualization, reduce errors**, and **improve customer experience**.
- 7. **Support and troubleshoot scalability, high availability**, performance, monitoring, **backup, and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Troubleshoot and **resolve issues in our development**, test, and production environments.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies, and processe**s to improve the speed, efficiency, and **scalability of continuous integration** environments.
- 10. Used **Jira as a Change Management**/ Work Management/ **Scrum Agile** Tool. **Updating the application team** in order to track the status of the user stories or defects.

## **Skills and Experience**

- 1. Embedding **Security** at every step of **SDLC** with various **DevSecOps tools**.
- 2. Expertise in **deploying at scale** various **containerized web**, **data applications**, and services using technologies such as **Docker**, **Kubernetes**, Elastic Kubernetes Service (**EKS**), Elastic Container Service (**ECS**), CloudWatch, and other **monitoring solutions**.
- 3. Strong experience in 40+ AWS services such as EC2, ELB ALB & NLB, ASG,

Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch AWS Lambda, API Gateway JIRA

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Hashicorp Certified - Terraform Associate

#### **EDUCATION**

**Education History** 

- IAM, CloudWatch, Relational Database Service (RDS), S3, etc.
- 4. Configured **AWS Security Services** such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, Cloud Trail, Config, and Guard Duty to secure resources at multiple layers.
- 5. Used **Terraform to build** multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- 6. Standardized the **Terraform modules** for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in **reducing the code time** and re-usability of the modules.
- 7. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through **Packer** and used **Ansible** for **Application configuration**.
- 8. Used **Jenkins Pipelines** to drive all **Micro Services** builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then **deployed to Kubernetes**/ECS/EKS, and managed the application with **various Kubernetes Objects** also **integrated** with **Jira and Slack to send** build state information.
- 9. **Optimize Jenkins container configurations** such as mount docker runtime inside **container as a volume**, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and **scripted Jenkins configurations** in to a Jenkinsfile to run **Single Pipeline** and **MultiBranch** Pipeline Jobs.
- 10. Experience in **administering Kubernetes** and a good understanding of manifest management with Helm along with expertise in Ingress Controller and Service mesh with **Istio for pod communication and encryption**.
- 11. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and integrated Terraform in **CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 12. Automated tasks related to System Health Checks, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks through Python Scripting.
- 13. Expert in configuring & operating **ELK/EFK Stack**; **ElasticSearch** for deep search and data analytics, **fluentD** for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and **Kibana for powerful** and beautiful data visualizations.
- 14. Used **Jira as change Management** and **Scrum Agile** tool. Updating the application team in order to track the status of the **user stories or defects**.
- 15. Configured **Prometheus Server** and its **components such as** Grafana, Alertmanager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications and Redis Data broker.
- 16. Successfully **upgraded the Kubernetes and Jenkins** by following the best practices and Effectively took the **back up of ETCD** database and performed timely **restore drills**.
- 17. Performed **Cost optimization with Kubecost** to avoid overspending on the resources.

## **Looking Forward To Learn**

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps, GCP
- 2. CKA Certification
- 3. New DevOps and DevSecOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.